hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft today
we decide
who wins the build off
and in order to do that i'm actually
going to have to ask scar and iskal
to get together with me to talk about it
because
i think at this point we are at build
height there is nowhere else for us to
go
that this is it everybody and honestly i
think that this looks so good as an
action scene
that i also don't feel it needs anything
else
so the last thing that we need to do is
just
stand on top of our houses and declare
who's the winner so i'm gonna ask
iskaland
oh no
oh
that was such a good elytra switch whoo
vex wings how did i get how did i end up
with some vex swings oh but either way
i'm gonna ask iskel and scar if they
would get online so that we can sort
this out i'm a pro minecrafter now
gentlemen
it's been
quite the build off wouldn't you say
mm-hmm well well well what have we here
uh well we have right here a house that
hits
255.5 and i know that that's exactly
half a block higher than scars over
there
yeah no this is uh two five five build
height i'm at build high yeah uh one
more add one more block to that scar
no two five five is build height no go
and place a block
try and place a block you guys are the
worst
you knew this the whole time you didn't
just drop me like a little
no blocks at all i feel like because
we're because we're so far away we
should be like
[Music]
so how do you guys think we should
finish the build-up i don't know but i
know one person being on 256 which has
been limited score should have been more
sportsmanlike and told me
don't worry
i can't hear you well i i brought along
a little summon summon just just in case
so now i
256.5
well
i kind of predicted that i mean greece
being green so
yeah uh-huh now we're two which i
brought
two five six point five right now i'm at
two five six five six two five zero
how
this is this is silly you can't win the
build off by point one of a block it's
just
no no this is silly this is silly we
should come up with a better way of
doing this okay well yeah to be fair i
mean my highest point is a
glass pane
yeah
and mine i think we all did pretty much
the same i think i think we should
i think we should do this properly like
an official winner to the build-off
and i think we should be really fair
about it and judge each other's builds
at on like criteria and then the person
with the highest score wins the build
off no questions asked
yeah oh i like that we so we don't we
don't score ourselves right no we don't
explore ourselves and we all have to
agree on the categories
before we go in sound fair
yes fair
and by default mumbo lost correct oh
yeah oh i think we can all agree
standing here
that mumbai
we've got some voting booths ready and
we've all agreed on it we've got our
books here everyone you take your book
from your voting booth because we've all
agreed on all of the categories that
we're going to be judging against they
are diversity which is you know how many
different things there are complexity
defense stability livability value
amusement and fear factor so now we need
to go and take our books and properly
inspect our opponents builds and give
them a score in each category out of
five and then we come back and we total
them all up and decide who's the winner
sounds good so
i'm going to start off by taking a look
at iskals so the first one is diversity
my goodness if we have a look at iskals
he's got the fish tank he's got the
house with fish tank with the up house
with the empire state building not the
eiffel tower i misspoke last episode
with a magnet with the moon with a space
station with an iceberg and the giant
dabbing penguin if that's not diversity
i don't know what is so i'm i'm going to
give iskall so i'll put five out of five
okay the next one is complexity how
complex is it the detail on the
buildings is not
the most like the moon is it's a perfect
sphere but it's not you know i think the
detail could be a bit better but overall
it's not that bad at all uh
three out of five i'm gonna crash while
i write this now remember that this is
totally just my opinion and you may
disagree with me but this is this is how
i feel about the build
okay so the next one is defense
well there's no defense here i've got to
say iskall this is the dabbing penguin
like i built a dragon a fire breathing
dragon and he built a dabbing penguin
unless that dabbing penguin's got
something up his sleeve i'm i'm not
gonna rate this highly on defense at all
like this just does this seems to have
just taken it actually he did the magnet
thing that's the only sort of offensive
thing that he's done so i'm gonna
i'm gonna give him quite a low score of
two for defense i don't think it's that
good then what's the next one stability
well it's pretty stable it's definitely
quite you know wide but it's very tall i
think i'm going to go for a solid three
you know somewhere directly in the
middle i think three out of five is a
good one now livability that means the
suitability for someone to actually in
survival minecraft live in this house
living in that aquarium would be a pain
you can actually live in that house in
the bottom you could live in the empire
state building you could live in that
house in there but it's it's a nightmare
to get to as is that as there's not
really anything in there that's not
livable so
i'm gonna go for somewhere in the middle
again i'm gonna say three out of five
for livability now value value is like
how much would you sell this building
for how
sellable is it that's really difficult
to answer like how how much would you
try and sell this build for
well it's got
it's got a lot on it it's got the moon
but i don't know whether the dabbing
penguin might set things off i'm just
i'm gonna go for three again because i
think i think i think there's pros and
cons to this one
amusement i mean i don't even need to
look i don't even need to look at it
dabbing penguin five
fear factor
fear factor don't really find this scary
i'm afraid iskall so i think you're
going to get a one for that all right so
let me just total this up iskal got 25
which is a pretty decent score he's done
quite well he's got a couple of fives
not too bad now we need to judge scars
build so diversity diversity so most of
his build is made up of scara the plant
so that's just one thing then you've got
the castle and then you've got the laser
beam house here so there's three
components to this
so i think i'm gonna i'm gonna stick to
that and i'm gonna i'm gonna say three
so three for diversity complexity oh boy
yeah this i mean this is a pretty
complex build making any kind of organic
in minecraft is an absolute nightmare
look at the lasers i'm gonna factor that
in the and then there's even more
complexity up here like working with all
this stained glass this is absolutely an
incredible build uh this is a five out
of five from me i think scar wins the
most on defense because he has been
pretty much in the the driver's seat of
a lot of the offensive so he's got a
laser beam
he's got a wizard
and he's got a cannon that's that's
quite a lot of firepower
so i'm i'm going to give him a quite a
strong four out of five there stability
stability will it fall over will it
topple over well it is a plant but it is
standing tall it is quite a strong part
i mean that is terrifying i think i'm
gonna go for i think i'm gonna go for
three so
livability well i'm afraid there's no
living in the giant plant that's just
not happening so the majority of this
build you cannot live in you can live in
this modern house
but would you want to live in this if
you had this scarra plant i i'm again
i'm not going to rate this too highly
for livability i think i think i think
it's quite hard to live in that
and then the value
i'm actually going to rate the value
really low and let me explain why
because i believe that this particular
build
was the reaction from
a nuclear core so this entire plant is
radioactive for me i'm gonna give that a
really low value because i would not buy
anything
that's dangerous like that uh amusement
i mean again this they've outdone me on
amusement they got the dabbing penguin
they got the giant wizard flower i i
can't i can't kid myself this has got to
be a five out of five absolutely
brilliant i i love this i love scars
build so much but fear factor see here's
the thing i'm torn on fear factor
because scar's little face isn't scary
scarra was terrifying really like
genuinely quite scary looking right up
until he added a wizard hat on it and
all of a sudden it wasn't that scary so
i'm going to add
i'm going to give you somewhere in the
middle for that so three well there's my
judging so according to my scores
scar has one from me but we have to see
what the other guys have judged as well
we've got to add up all the scores so
that it's fair has everyone got their
final scores
yep okay
it actually took quite a long time to
judge both of these so i think instead
of going over each individual one we
should just go for the total and then
add them up to see who the winner is and
then afterwards we'll put our books back
in the voting booth and you can go and
see what the other person uh gave you
all right okay i think we should sign
them first so that no one yes
with the scores yes no cheating okay i
just want to check that i did the math
correctly there we go green score
okay so i'll go first iskal
so sorry
you lost online you got 25
oh
scar got 26. he'd literally beat you by
one point
you hear that scarra
one point i think i think it was the
fear factor because his was a bit
scarier than the dabbing penguin
i i yeah i can see i can dab on i can
agree now i can dab on that
[Laughter]
all right my score green yeah 29 disco
30. oh
yes by one point
but one point again
oh that's my last house oh no i was so
impressed with the 29
it's the up house man it's a disney
thing
you've got disney points you got a bonus
that's true yeah that's true i knew i
had this car there okay okay also the
penguin by the way this the penguin was
both amusing and fearful at the same
time it hurt my soul and it brought joy
to my soul so okay so i've got 29. this
girl's got 30. so we know yours is gal
yours is 30 plus 25. so you got 55. 45
55. yeah so 55. so it all comes down to
what iskal has given us okay okay okay
all right okay i gave
green yeah
26 points
26 points yeah so what was
so
what's green score then did we know 6 26
plus 9 55 50 we call it exactly the same
score oh yeah
oh no wait what are we tied yeah we're
tied what did you give scar
i gave scott 29 points
29 29 how much did he have i gave him
26. let's go give me another point i'll
give you a dollar
he's 55. you're joking
are you kidding me
no someone checked them out i'm not
confident enough with numbers
we've all got 55.
55 points
oh
can we just agree that mumbo loses
yeah
yeah i said yeah i think i mean
if that's not if that's not a draw i
don't know what is i'm not going through
that again i came through that again
that's crazy
well we're not doing a race at the
bottom gg no we're not doing a race to
the bottom
right well if you want to see the scores
that i gave you they are there for you
to have a look at oh you gave me five
for defense nice is it because of the
solely because of the dragon yeah that
thing is freaky look at that look at the
fire come on look at that thing all
right then well i i don't know what to
say like this this build off wasn't
really planned so i guess thanks
it was awesome thank you and yeah yeah
thanks for all the laughters thanks for
all the belly eggs going through the
nether portal see ya
next next if this happens next season
bigger and better next time bigger and
better that took a lot longer than i
thought it would but i've got to say i'm
kind of relieved because
i think that no one really should win
this amazing build-off that's happened
here
so overall i think the result is really
good but that took such a long time that
i've neglected it so everyone needs to
say goodbye to the build off because
this is how it's going to stay
for the rest of the season however over
here you will notice that there's two
big things that have been added and i've
not really talked about them so this
over here is cubs mini game called
ravager run
and boy oh boy is it fun we played a
quick game and to be honest with you the
game
it took quite a long time so i'm just
gonna sort of put in some highlights
here of what the game's about basically
you've got to run
into the town over here
and you've got to find colored blocks
and run back in the meantime all of
these ravages chase you around and if
you get stuck in a corner yeah they
really hurt and then over here we've got
iskall's unplayed mini game that i think
will be happening soon
so i got thinking
there's basically
mini games happening over here
so
why don't we as hermitcraft
make this area a proper mini game
district and we could like build this in
sort of a theme park fashion
type thing there's like a border here so
you can see all this land can be used
and then everyone can make their own
mini games
and come over here to play them in their
spare time
i think that would be a really really
cool thing to happen since we've already
got two massive minigames so what i'm
gonna do
is i'm gonna just make the entrance
because i do need to sort of
put this to the other people on
hermitcraft because i can't make this
whole thing by myself but if we start
clearing this out what i was thinking is
we could make a little entrance here
and call it like hermit land or
something hermit land that's the name of
the the park here
and we'll all make our own little mini
games
for us to make so the first thing we've
got to do
is clear out this area
and get something built
now this time lapse is going to make you
laugh because
you think mumbo jumbo is a spoon wait
until you see what i did so i cleared
out the area and then i wrote that i
wrote
her
herms land this is meant to be a sign
to a new place called hermit land and i
didn't even bother to count that hermit
has six letters so i had to rip it all
down and do the whole thing over again
actually spelling out hermit it looks a
lot better
i'm such an idiot sometimes there we go
the very start of hermit land
now i don't actually want to do too much
for a start i don't know if this is
going to stay this is just like the very
first draft i don't know what the
style's going to be
nothing what i thought i was going to do
with this is simply to show where the
entrance could be as it's like right
next to hermitville we could make a path
coming out here and then this this just
seemed like a really natural place for
this entrance to go
and then it goes straight over the river
and into
the mini game district as i've
affectionately called hermitland i mean
i don't really mind this can change but
hopefully we can get the other hermits
on board this gigantic project and maybe
in the next couple of episodes
we could make our own mini game
hopefully something
not quite as difficult as ravager run i
don't know how cub got as many ravages
as he did this this must have taken him
weeks
weeks and weeks to do this so hopefully
we can create something a little bit
more simple
for the mini game district but i think
this will be a lot of fun i think that
entrance really does sit quite nicely
there
now as you know from the previous
episodes we are down to our last diamond
and i've decided not to have the diamond
spawned back in i think it'll be a lot
of fun trying to get them back and i
actually learned of a way that we can
make money back
unfortunately
it's via concorp
so
basically cub and scar have introduced
something called a buy back scheme so
the shops that you buy stuff from for
example
the whole lot of terra cotta has a buy
back program as you can see here concord
buyback basically you can sell them
stock
for them so you could purchase one
diamond per stack or you could sell them
two stacks for a diamond
so
that could work quite well because i've
got quite a lot of excess
materials and that could be a very quick
way for me to make some
diamonds so if we take a look at what
we've got available
there we go there's some terracotta if i
just grab as much terracotta
oh boy
i kind of like the mess but i also i'm
struggling a little bit to keep up with
everything okay i don't have as much
terra cotta as i thought
but that is still two diamonds that i
didn't have we're crawling our way back
and hopefully
they have another buyback scheme at the
glass shop that's my next port of call
oh they do they have a buy back program
for the glass hold on so we are buying
back two stacks of clear glass for one
diamond
hold on
hold on let me just check something two
stacks of clear glass for one diamond
two stacks of clear glass for one
diamond
and we're selling
three stacks
for one diamond of sand
that means i can force concorp
to buy sahara sand by turning it into
glass
now if that's not stonks i don't know
what is
so if i just go and do
i have to do it nine at a time can't
believe i'm shopping at sahara
for concorp this is this is hilarious i
hope this works out the way i hope it
will
okay
it is ready order is coming in
oh sahara you're gonna make me some
diamonds
there we go one two three
one two three
this is like printing money is that it
that should be that's that is that is
nine that's a full shulker box of sand
wow sahara worked
so i now owe sahara nine diamonds i've
only got two at the moment but there
should be nine for one diamond okay just
bear with me because this is this is
gonna work out i promise we then just
gotta super smell all of this sand into
glass
and now we wait for a little while while
we get this glass in we've got a shulker
box full of glass and i've even added
some of my personal glass in here and i
didn't even waste any time because
basically i was just afk in here while i
was doing other work so i didn't lose
any time waiting for the glass
this is just brilliant all right so
let's head back over to concord
all right so if i put the shulker box
down we take out all the glass and we do
the buy back so basically if this is
full how many stacks is that that is 26
stacks so this should be 13 diamonds
there we go
we just made
money by forcing concorp
to buy ow
to buy our sand
if only they'd put more diamonds in here
they're gonna have to restock this
because i i'm gonna i'm gonna exploit
this the best i can and then the money
or nine diamonds of it goes straight
into sahara which will
work towards you know paying me anyway
and then i've paid off the sahara debt
boom i made six diamonds and zahara gets
nine diamonds which makes its way to me
anyway
that is what i call free money i didn't
have to work very hard for that at all
i'll keep this glass here
for when they restock their diamonds
and then i'll grab myself some more
diamonds because i've now paid sahara
off so that means all of this is pure
profit diamonds i think we just beat
concorp at their own game and i'm afraid
that is all from me today thank you very
much for watching everyone it was
awesome to see the build off i'm very
happy with the result i think it's quite
fair actually
in a weird turn of events i was i would
be very surprised if i won
so i'm very happy with the 55 each
and we have started hermit land the new
gaming district
and we just made concorde give us
diamonds what a fantastic episode see
you in the next one good bye